so in Genesis 1:26 in fact if you can
can you go ahead and read it this is
1:26 good when when I got a chance to
hear this on the set I had the recorded
you on the phone yeah and then I shared
it with my girlfriend I was like oh no
you have to hear this yeah then God said
let us make man in our image according
to our likeness let them have dominion
over the fish of the sea over the birds
of the air and over the cattle over all
the earth and over every creeping thing
that creeps on the earth
okay so Genesis 1:26 and in in one of my
online classes I actually just uses this
example a few weeks ago it's a live
online class and so I was talking with
my students and they were like oh you
know and we just kind of walked through
this and built it together Wow right so
Dennis at power of the Lamb and calm
okay so and the class is called photo
theology so I'm taking them to Genesis
1:26 right and basically here's the idea
behind it we're looking at this verse in
a way that we have not looked at it
before we're using some different
techniques we're using dimensions where
you using this principle called quest
questioning the text right we approach a
text do you just read the text or do you
ask the text questions a good detective
is always going to ask questions right
when you read Genesis 1:26 you should
try to come up with at least 20
questions for that text Wow in our class
because of a specific principle we used
we came up with 20 questions first and
then I introduced this this new
principle and then we came up with a
hundred questions for Genesis 1:26 100
questions
Wow all right 100 questions each one of
those questions can be a study in and of
itself in other words you could be
studying Genesis 1:26 for a very very
very very very right so I'm going to
kind of juice
some of the things from Genesis 1:26 and
bring it to the Book of Daniel so in
Genesis 1:26 you have God creating man
in His image and in his likeness
basically meaning that God that man
reflected the character of God there are
two kingdoms that you find in Genesis
1:26 there is the kingdom of man and
then there's the animal kingdom mm-hm
God gave man dominion over the animal
kingdom right when man is in the image
of God he has dominion over the animal
kingdom so what happens is that man ends
up sinning and man sins through the
influence of a serpent so when he sings
under the influence of a serpent he now
becomes subject mm-me now but he loses
the image of God he's no longer in the
image of God but now he begins to
reflect the image of the animal I'm
gonna use the word beast see what I just
did yeah then you use a term serpent
yeah look how my mind is thinking right
I didn't use the term serpent it is a
serpent obviously but the serpent is a
beast right in my mind I'm thinking hmm
hmm wow man lost his image lost the
image of God so whose image is he
reflecting now yeah he's reflecting the
image of the beast hold on hold on
doesn't the book of Revelation talk
about the image of the Beast so what
happens this man begins to reflect the
animal nature Cain killing Abel
animalistic the that the condition of
men's hearts before the flood yes evil
continually animalistic and so we began
to look traces principle of this animal
nature instead of the divine nature whoa
inside of every one of us is this war
between the image of God and the image
of the beast who we gonna act like who
are we going to reflect then wait a
minute so the reason that the book of
Daniel
uses beasts to reflect the kingdoms of
men is because God is trying to tell us
this is what man has become this is what
the kingdoms of men have become they
have become brutal animalistic look at
the characteristics of the lion the bear
the leopard the forth terrible beast
that the the Beast of Revelation these
beasts in a certain way reflect certain
characteristics of wicked humanity and
so now no wonder
Nebuchadnezzar was turned like a beast
in Daniel chapter 6 right that picture
is God saying you want you want to act
like a beast alright you want to you
want to this is what you dis name is you
want to reflect I'm gonna let you
reflect this image mmm so now that the
plan of salvation really boils down to
this God is trying to remove the animal
nature and restore the image of God and
when he restores the image of God look I
want you to note the connections that
I'm making right when the image of God
is restored in man he will once again
have dominion over the beasts but
there's more because it's not just gonna
have dominion over the Beast
who did he have dominion over in the
beginning the beasts from the sea the
beasts from the earth and the beasts in
the air wait a minute wait a minute wait
a minute doesn't the book of Revelation
talk about a beast from the sea a beast
from the earth and the dragon was a
prince of the who's the Prince of the
power of the air whoa so in a sense when
the church reflects the image of God
mm-hm they have nothing to fear
regarding the beast from the sea right
or the beast from the earth or the
dragon who is the Prince of the power of
the air now I'm beginning to see now
Genesis 1:26 is just pregnant with the
gospel
this is what God is trying he's trying
to give me dominion over the beast in me
now I realize if I don't get dominion
over the beast in me I am in no way
shape or form ready to get dominion over
the beast from the sea or from the earth
I will I will receive the mark of the
beast because I'm already reflecting his
image Wow
now take that back to Daniel chapter 2
again I want you to see how these
connections are happening right if I'm
just reading Genesis 1:26
and I'm reading it just what it
literally says there's no way I'm making
these connections right if I'm staying
in the ink yep okay I'm just talking
about you know this what happened in the
beginning I'm not looking at the
spiritual connotation of that text I'm
not doing away with the literal right
I'm not doing away with the first
dimension right but I've just
dimensionalized you see what I'm saying
now I've brought that Genesis 1:26 I
brought it into the fourth dimension how
it relates to the church yeah I've
brought it into the third dimension how
it relates to me practically I've
brought it in to the Christ dimension
this is what Christ is trying to restore
in me it's it's crossing all these
dimensions I had dimensionalized the
text yes now I'm going to take it Daniel
2 because in Daniel 2 we have an image
of a man right right but in Daniel 7 we
have that same thing in the image of of
beasts so what does God trying to tell
us again he's trying to tell us look
this is the condition of the kingdoms of
men right check out Daniel chapter 2
Daniel 2 Babylon medo-persia Greece Rome
head of gold chest arms of silver belly
and thighs of brass legs of iron toes of
iron and clay right but these four
medals represent different kingdoms now
it's the kingdom these kingdoms are the
kingdoms of men mm-hmm the image is the
image of a man when we think about
Daniel 2 we typically think these
represent the nation's right and that
would be actually the fourth dimension a
prophetic dimension this is how this
relates to the church as a whole
but now let's take Daniel 2 and let's
look at it in the third dimension how
does this relate to me because you see
it's the image of a man mm-hmm
could Daniel to not just be about the
result of kingdoms that reject God but
could it also be showing us that this is
the result of the man that rejects God
mm-hmm the man that rejects God is gonna
fall just like the kingdoms fell mm-hmm
why pride goes before destruction and a
haughty spirit before Paul
so this kingdom representing represented
by man also points to what happens to me
when I reject Christ because notice how
the image starts gold but then it
deteriorates to silver brass iron in
other words the metals become harder the
longer that I reject God oh good this
state was trying to get us to be iron
hearted and reject God all together
which is what Rome did by the way they
crucified Christ Satan's trying to get a
Saku safai cry so fresh so the longer we
go without God is the more hardened we
get mm-hmm look at the metals as they
devalue as they go on
Wow you know what what the longer I go
without God the less valuable I that the
Lord let me not say the less valuable
the less value ba and but the more we
lose value if you will for others around
us for ourselves mm-hmm now check out
these four kingdoms right one kingdom
represented by the head one by the chest
one by the stomach in the thighs and one
by the legs right four kingdoms kingdom
of the mind kingdom of the heart hmm
kingdom of the appetites
kingdom of the directions hmm so what is
God trying to do God is trying to
conquer our kingdoms Wow
now the Bible says a kingdom divided
against itself cannot stand right so I
want you to think about this if I'm
serving God
like I like Bible study it's all
cerebral for me you know man I like the
word I like the word but I don't know
how to treat my neighbor I don't know
how to love God with my heart I don't
know how to treat others with love I can
claim that I'm a Christian all day long
I can claim that you know I'm a Bible
leaving you know three angels messages
all day long and if my heart has hate if
I despise if I have anger towards other
people I can clean this all day long
this kingdom is divided and Jesus does
not dwell in a divided Kingdom
he's not gonna rule the mind while Satan
has the heart or he's not going to have
the heart while Satan has the appetites
and desires and if you're not willing to
direct your path give you a path to him
and walk in his ways he's not gonna
it's either the whole kingdom is his or
it's none of his at all yes he does not
share the kingdom with Satan oh that's
good so I was sharing it in our in our
study that when a person's baptized it's
the fall of their kingdoms right it's
that stone Jesus Christ coming and
destroying that king those kingdoms all
those kingdoms fall Lord I am all yours
mind heart appetite and desires and path
and direction everything is yours and I
like how Daniel 2 puts it the wind comes
and blew away the remnants of that old
image that's what God wants to do with
us he wants to make us a new creature or
new creation in him it is rich this is
Genesis 1:26 this is how he recreates us
in His image it is what image daniel
chapter 2 guys that image needs to fall
why because that image is really an
image of beasts Daniel 7 that's all
these techniques taken together and the
result is when I look at Genesis 1:26 I
see something that is just like